Finding Aid for David E. Cole papers, 1951-2003
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Associations and Government
  - Society of Automotive Engineers (SAE)
    - Conferences
      - International Congress and Exposition
        - Brochure, 1982 (Box 9)
        - Keynote session for Congress and Exposition, 1982 (Box 9)
        - 1984 (Box 9)
        - Plastic recycling session, 1995 (Box 9)
      - International Pacific Conference
        - Conference, 1981; 2 folders (Box 9)
        - General Committee meeting, 1985 (Box 9)
      - Convergence
        - With paper, 1986 (Box 10)
        - 1996 (Box 10)
      - Greenbrier meeting, 1992 (Box 10)
      - Management of Technology panel at the SAE Annual Business Meeting, 1982 (Box 10)
      - IECEC (Intersociety Energy Conversion Engineering Conference), 1980s (Box 10)
      - IMechE (Institution of Mechanical Engineers) Conference for, 1984 (Box 10)
    - Ralph R. Teetor award, 1967-1969 (Box 10)
    - Edward N. Cole Award (Box 10)
    - Photograph of Cole with award (Box 10)
    - Election to Fellow, 1986-1988 (Box 10)
    - Ballot for Election of Officers for, 1980; 1981 (Box 10)
    - Students and education
      - Student Activity Program panel discussion, 1969-1970 (Box 10)
      - "Engineering Opportunity Outlook" panel, 1973 (Box 10)
      - Michigan students (includes photos) (Box 10)
    - Tune-up Clinic (includes correspondence), 1970s (Box 10)
    - Annual Report, 1987 (Box 10)
    - General Correspondence (Box 10)
    - Poster contest judge's book (Box 10)
    - Paper draft on automotive technologies, 1979 (Box 10)
    - Publications and pamphlets (Box 10)
    - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Government Projects
    This subseries documents three government projects: the Cooperative Automotive Research Program (CARP), the U.S.-Canada Automotive Select Panel and the Auto-in-Michigan (AIM) Project. CARP was a program supported by the government and automotive industry that sponsored automotive projects in 12 major research areas. Cole was the Chairman of the Engine/Fuel and Thermal/Fluid Sciences Advisory Panel. This subseries contains meeting materials and correspondence from that project. Cole was a member of the U.S.-Canada Automotive Select Panel and was involved in the Competitiveness Subcommittee. Materials on this panel include correspondence, meeting minutes and preliminary proposal from OSAT. The Auto-in-Michigan (AIM) Project was created to "target the changing automotive sector with focused economic development programs" (AIM Interim Report). Cole served on the Central Research Team. Included in this subseries are reports from this project.
    - Cooperative Automotive Research Program (CARP)
      - Formation and Framework, 1979-1980 (Box 10)
      - Research, meetings and notes, 1979-1980 (Box 11)
      - Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 11)
      - Progress report and request for action, 1980 (Box 11)
      - Position paper for the Department of Transportation (DOT), 1979 (Box 11)
    - U.S.-Canada Automotive Select Panel Competitiveness Subcommittee
      - Preliminary progress report, 1989 (Box 11)
      - Preliminary proposal by the Office for the Study of Automotive Transportation (OSAT), 1991 (Box 11)
      - Meetings
        - First meeting, January 1991 (Box 11)
        - February 1991 (Box 11)
      - "Summary Presentation of Final Report: North American Competitiveness Study -- Phase 1,", 1991 (Box 11)
      - U.S./Canadian free trade (Box 11)
      - Correspondence and miscellaneous, 1989-1992 (Box 11)
    - Auto-in-Michigan (AIM)
      - Interim report, 1985 (Box 11)
      - Report, 1985 (Box 11)
      - Michigan's major independent automotive supplier facilities (Box 11)
      - "Anticipating Employment Change in Chrysler in Michigan ", 1986-1990 (Box 11)
      - "Anticipating Employment Change in Ford in Michigan ", 1985-1990 (Box 11)
  - Hearings and Testimonies
    - Testimony; International Finance and Economic Stabilization Subcommittees of the Senate Banking Committee, 1980 (Box 12)
    - Harbeck's testimony before the Senate Hearings, 1981 (Box 12)
    - Testimony before the Subcommittee on Transportation, Aviation & Materials, 1981; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Department of Energy Hearing, 1989 (Box 12)
  - Patents
    - Patent descriptions, 1970s-1980s (Box 12)
    - Correspondence, 1970s-1980s (Box 12)
  - Organizations
    The Organizations subseries documents Cole's activities with various government and professional entities, including his consulting work. This subseries includes materials from Cole's activities as a member of the NASA Space Systems and Technical Advisory Committee, and the Energy Engineering Board of the National Research Council.
    - 3M (Box 12)
    - AAM (Alliance of Automobile Manufacturers), 2002 (Box 12)
    - AAAM (American Auto Manufacturers Association), 1999 (Box 12)
    - Accenture, 2001 (Box 12)
    - Advanced Electron Beams (Box 12)
    - AIAG (Automotive Industry Action Group), 1990s (Box 12)
    - Alcan Aluminum (Box 12)
    - American Iron & Steel Institute (AISI) (Box 12)
    - American Society of Body Engineers, 1997 (Box 12)
    - Ames, 2000 (Box 12)
    - Andersen Consulting, 1990s-2000s (Box 12)
    - Ann Arbor Clean Cities, 2000 (Box 12)
    - Argonne Lab, 2002-2003 (Box 12)
    - ASC, Inc., 2001 (Box 12)
    - A.T. Kearney Inc., 1996 (Box 12)
    - Auto Pacific, 1990s (Box 12)
    - Auto Steel Partnership, 1990s (Box 12)
    - Automotive Consulting Group, 1980s-1990s (Box 12)
    - Automotive Hall of Fame
      - 1999-2001 (Box 12)
      - 2002-2003 (Box 13)
    - Automotive Market Research Council, 1995 (Box 13)
    - California Air Resources Board, 1993-1994 (Box 13)
    - Economic Dinner Group, 1990s-2000s (Box 13)
    - Energy Engineering Board
      - Energy engineering (Box 13)
      - Meetings
        - May 1991 (Box 13)
        - September 1991, May 1992 (Box 13)
        - March 1994 (Box 13)
        - June 1994 (Box 13)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 13)
    - Environmental Research Institute of Michigan (ERIM)
      - ERIM/CAR Auto Body Consortium (ABC), 1990s-2000s (Box 13)
      - "The Educational Role of the Environmental Research Institute of Michigan", 1979 (Box 13)
    - ESD (Engineering Society of Detroit), 1995 (Box 13)
    - MEDC (Michigan Economic Development Corporation), 2000s (Box 13)
    - MEMA (Motor and Equipment Manufacturers Association), 1999-2000 (Box 13)
    - MMTC (Midwest Manufacturing Technology Advisory Council), 1990s-2000s (Box 13)
    - Mott Foundation, 1980s-2000s (Box 13)
    - NADA, National Automotive Dealers Charitable Foundation, 1990s-2000s (Box 13)
    - National Academies, 2001 (Box 13)
    - NASA
      - SSTAC (Space Systems and Technology Advisory Committee) and Informal Subcommittee on Energy Technology
        - 1970s-1980s, 2 folders (Box 14)
        - 1980s (Box 14)
        - 1981-1983 (Box 14)
      - Publications, 1980s (Box 14)
    - National Pollution Prevention Center, 1995 (Box 14)
    - NIST (National Institute of Standards and Technology) (Box 14)
    - OESA (Original Equipment Suppliers Association)
      - Board of Directors and miscellaneous, 2000s; 2 folders (Box 14)
      - Board of Directors Handbook for, 2002-2003 (Box 14)
    - OTA (Office of Technology Assessment)
      - Correspondence and miscellaneous, 1970s-1980s (Box 14)
      - Working paper for OTA, 1979 (Box 14)
    - SAA (Society of Automotive Analysts), 2001 (Box 14)
    - SME (Society of Manufacturing Engineers), 2003 (Box 14)
    - Society of Plastics Engineers, 1980s (Box 14)
    - State of Michigan
      - Governor Engler (Box 14)
      - Japan Trade Initiative Meeting, 2/7/1992 (Box 14)
      - MAP (Michigan Automotive Partnership)
        - 1990s (Box 15)
        - 1990s-2000s (Box 15)
      - Miscellaneous, 1990s-2000s (Box 15)
    - Southwest Research Institute, 1990s (Box 15)
    - Suppliers Association (discussion of creation), 1982-1983 (Box 15)
    - TACOM (Tank-automotive and Armaments Command)
      - Army and automotive industry (Box 15)
      - ARC (Automotive Research Center)
        - Correspondence and ARC Proposal, 1990s (Box 15)
        - Reports
          - Scientific and Technical Progress Report for, 8/1994-2/1995 (Box 15)
          - Progress, Status, and Management Report
            - For, 8/1994-2/1995 (Box 15)
            - For, 3/1995-8/1995 (Box 15)
          - Scientific and Technical Report Summary
            - For, 9/1994-8/1995 (Box 15)
            - For, 3/1995-8/1995 (Box 15)
            - For, 9/1995-2/1996 (Box 15)
    - UM Technical Advisory Committee, 2002 (Box 15)
    - United States Government
      - Congressional Economic Leadership Institute (Box 15)
      - Dr Linda Brandt, National Defense University, 1999 (Box 15)
      - IRS (Box 15)
      - President's Export Council (Box 15)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 15)
    - Washtenaw County, 1996 (Box 15)
    - Wayne County, 1995-1996 (Box 15)
    - Western New York Economic Development Corporation, 1994 (Box 15)
    - Universities and Colleges
      - Michigan State University
        - Design Conference and automotive research (Box 16)
        - Gib Butler (Box 16)
      - Northwood University (Box 16)
      - Washtenaw Community College, 1980s-1990s (Box 16)
      - Miscellaneous Universities (Box 16)
- Company Files
  The Company Files document Cole's business activities with United States and international corporations, including consulting work, research, arranging corporate sponsors for OSAT and discussion of the Traverse City Management Briefing Seminar. For more documentation on Cole's consulting work, please see the Consulting subseries found in the Research series.
  - United States
    The United States subseries consists of companies that were headquartered in the United States, although many of these corporations also had offices in other countries. Cole served as a member of several boards and committees for US companies, often in the role of a consultant. At Johnson Controls, Cole was a member of two Technical Advisory Boards, the Automotive Systems Group (where he served as chairman) and the Battery Group. He was also a member of Johnson Control's Technical Advisory Group, which was made up of Technical Advisory Board chairpersons. Cole served on the Board of Directors for Mechanical Dynamics as an Audit Committee member and did consulting work for United Technologies Automotive (UTA) as a member of their Technical Advisory Committee. He was on the project team for Ernst & Young's Car Company of the Future project, and also served on the Editorial Advisory Board of Automotive Leadership. This subseries contains material on General Motors, including Cole's correspondence about conferences, presentations and automotive industry issues. Materials on Ford include Cole's correspondence and information on simultaneous development.
    - Arthur D. Little, Inc., 19980s-1990s (Box 16)
    - A. O. Smith, 1994 (Box 16)
    - Bay Windpower (Box 16)
    - Bayer, 1995 (Box 16)
    - Business Building Knowledge (BBK), 2002 (Box 16)
    - Bozell/Chrysler, 1990s (Box 16)
    - Cheveron Research and Technology Company
      - Correspondence, 1980s-1990s (Box 16)
      - Reports and papers, 1989; 1991 undated (Box 16)
      - OSAT reports, 1990; 1992 (Box 16)
      - Internal combustion engine (Box 16)
      - "Transportation 2005" (Box 16)
      - Alcohol (Box 16)
    - Chrysler Corporation, 1980s-1990s (Box 16)
    - Corio (Box 16)
    - Dana Corporation, 1990s-2000s (Box 16)
    - Delco Electronics (includes slides), 1990s (Box 16)
    - Donnelly Corporation, 1980s-1990s (Box 16)
    - DOW Chemical Company, 1990s (Box 16)
    - Deloitte & Touche, 1990s (Box 16)
    - DSM Polymer, 1999 (Box 16)
    - Dura Corporation (Box 16)
    - EDS (Electronic Data Systems), 1990s (Box 16)
    - Elm International, 1995-1996 (Box 16)
    - Environmental Dynamics, Inc.
      - Board meeting and correspondence, 1970s (Box 16)
      - Survey for Aluminum Association, 1976 (Box 16)
      - Automotive Testing, 1980 (Box 16)
    - Ernst & Young
      - Car Company of the Future
        - Advisory Committee meetings, 1991 (Box 16)
        - Correspondence (Box 16)
        - Stock letters (Box 16)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 16)
        - Correspondence, 1990s (Box 17)
        - Projects (Box 17)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 17)
    - Executive Recruiters, 1994 (Box 17)
    - Fifth Third Bank, 2002 (Box 17)
    - Financial Times, 1999 (Box 17)
    - Focus: Hope (Box 17)
    - Ford
      - Organization information, 1990s-2000s (Box 17)
      - Correspondence, 1990s (Box 17)
      - Projects (Box 17)
      - News releases and articles (Box 17)
      - Simultaneous Development, 1994 (Box 17)
      - Notes (Box 17)
    - Free Markets (includes CD) (Box 17)
    - Future Three Software, Inc., 1990s (Box 17)
    - Gemini, 2 folders (Box 17)
    - General Electric (GE) (Box 17)
    - General Motors (GM)
      - Subject
        - B-O-C (Buick-Oldsmobile-Cadillac) Group Supplier Assessment, 1986 (Box 17)
        - C-P-C (Chevrolet-Pontiac-Canada), 1980s-1990s (Box 17)
        - Centers of Expertise, 1985 (Box 17)
        - Delco Electronics, 1990s (Box 17)
        - Packard Electric, 1980s-1990s (Box 17)
        - Proposals (Box 17)
        - Purchasing, 1990s (Box 17)
        - Saginaw Steering, 1980s-1990s (Box 17)
        - Technology Center corporate strategic planning, 1986 (Box 17)
        - Advanced Engineering (Box 17)
        - Service Proposal (Box 17)
        - Inland Division (Box 17)
        - New Departure Division (Box 17)
        - GM/IBM Proposal, 1999 (Box 17)
        - Draft of "Priorities and Focus," which gives a history of GM, 2000 (Box 17)
        - Global Automotive Manufacturing and Technology, 2001 (Box 17)
      - Chronological
        - 1989-1991, 3 folders (Box 17)
        - 1992, 2 folders (Box 18)
        - 1993, 2 folders (Box 18)
        - 1994, 3 folders (Box 18)
        - 1995, 2 folders (Box 18)
          (includes photos)
        - 1998-2003 (scattered), 3 folders (Box 18)
    - GMI, 1980s-1990s (Box 18)
    - Grand Haven Stamped Products, 1993-1994 (Box 18)
    - Hedge & Company, 2001; 2003 (Box 18)
    - I2 Technologies, 1990s (Box 18)
    - IBM, 1990s-2000s (Box 18)
    - Inacom Corporation, 1990s (Box 18)
    - Johnson Controls
      - Annual reports, 1991-1992 (Box 18)
      - Company information (Box 18)
      - Technical Advisory Board (TAB) and Technical Advisory Group (TAG) charter, 1994 (Box 18)
      - Technical Advisory Group (TAG) meetings
        - 1987-1988 (Box 18)
        - 1989 (Box 18)
        - 1990 (Box 18)
        - 1991, 2 folders (Box 19)
        - 1992 (Box 19)
        - 1993, 2 folders (Box 19)
        - 1994 (Box 19)
        - 1995-1996 (Box 19)
      - Technical Advisory Board (TAB) meetings
        - 1993-1994 (Box 19)
        - 1995, 2 folders (Box 19)
        - 1996 (Box 19)
        - 1997 (Box 19)
        - 1998 (Box 19)
        - 1999-2000 (Box 19)
      - Technical Advisory Workshop (Box 19)
      - News releases, 1996 (Box 19)
      - Prince Corporation Technical Studies Group visit (Box 19)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 19)
    - Lear Seating Corporation, 1995 (Box 19)
    - Michigan Automotive Research Corporation (MARCO)
      - Company information (Box 19)
      - Business plans, 1988; 1996 (Box 19)
      - Miscellaneous, 1980s-1990s (Box 19)
    - Masco Industries, Inc., 1990s (Box 19)
    - Mechanical Dynamics
      - Annual report and "playbooks,", 1990s (Box 19)
      - ADAMS software, 1980s-1990s (Box 20)
      - Meetings and miscellaneous (Box 20)
    - Metal Power Industries Federation, 1980s-1990s (Box 20)
    - Michelin, 2002 (Box 20)
    - MSC Software
      - Annual report and company information, 1990s (Box 20)
      - Financial information for stockholders, 1998-1999 (Box 20)
      - 2nd Worldwide Automotive Conference (includes CD), 2000 (Box 20)
      - "Worldwide Aerospace Conference and Technology Showcase,", 2002 (Box 20)
    - Nassin Uddin
      - Discussion items with Cole (Box 20)
      - Automotive Leadership
        - Editorial Advisory Board meeting (Box 20)
        - Media kit (Box 20)
      - E-autoshows.com board meeting and business concept (Box 20)
      - Global Powertrain Congress (Box 20)
      - Global Automotive Management Council (Box 20)
    - National Educator, 1996 (Box 20)
    - National Center for Manufacturing Sciences, 1997; 2003 (Box 20)
    - Noranda, 2000 (Box 20)
    - North Star Steel/Cargill, 1996 (Box 20)
    - New United Motors Manufacturing, Inc (NUMMI), 1980s (Box 20)
    - Orbital
      - Annual reports and company information, 1989-1990 (Box 20)
      - Correspondence, 1980s-1990s (Box 20)
      - Orbital Combustion Process Engine (Box 20)
      - News releases and clippings (Box 20)
    - Parametric Technology, 1990s-2000s (Box 20)
    - Perception, 1996 (Box 20)
    - Phillips Petroleum, 1996 (Box 20)
    - Pinnacle, 2000 (Box 20)
    - Plante & Moran, LLP, 1997-1998 (Box 20)
    - PolyDisplay, 2002 (Box 20)
    - QAD, 1994-1995 (Box 20)
    - Raytech (Box 20)
    - Rieter Automotive Systems, 1990s (Box 20)
    - R.J. Tower Corporation, 1980s-1990s (Box 20)
    - R.L. Polk, 2003 (Box 20)
    - Rockwell, 1996 (Box 20)
    - Roland Berger, 2002 (Box 20)
    - Rosen Motors, 1997 (Box 20)
    - Ryder Trucking, 1992 (Box 20)
    - SAS Institute, Inc., 1990s (Box 20)
    - Siemens, 1990s (Box 20)
    - Sigma Associates
      - Correspondence, 1990s-2000s (Box 20)
      - Papers and presentations
        - Automotive Diversity, 1989-1991 (Box 20)
        - Global Industry, 1990s (Box 21)
        - Learning, 1990-1992 (Box 21)
        - Management (Box 21)
        - "Measuring Cost and Value" (Auto/Steel Partnership Product Development Program)
          - Draft, 1990 (Box 21)
          - "Management Highlights" (Box 21)
        - Steel, 1986; 1990-1991 (Box 21)
        - Suppliers, 1980s-2000s (Box 21)
      - Articles on automotive industry (Box 21)
    - Silicon Graphics, 1992; 1996 (Box 21)
    - Solectrica, 1996 (Box 21)
    - Soligen Technologies, 1996 (Box 21)
    - Soltia Inc., 1998 (Box 21)
    - SPX (Sealed Power), 1996 (Box 21)
    - Textron, 1908s-1990s (Box 21)
    - Thomas Group, 1997 (Box 21)
    - Tire Business, 1993 (Box 21)
    - TirMentor Group, 2000s (Box 21)
    - TRW, Inc., 1997-1998 (Box 21)
    - UAW (International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America), 1996 (Box 21)
    - Union Carbide (SAE paper), 1993 (Box 21)
    - United Technologies Automotive (UTA)
      - Company information and newspapers, 1990s (Box 21)
      - Consulting and Technical Advisory Committee
        - 1992 (Box 21)
        - 1993 (Box 21)
        - 1994 (Box 21)
        - 1995 (Box 21)
      - Cole's paper on system sourcing, 1994 (Box 21)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 21)
    - United Training Services (Box 21)
    - United States Council for Automotive Research
      - "Media Information" (includes photos) (Box 21)
      - Leadership Day
        - Agenda and presentations, 1996 (Box 21)
        - Cole's presentation on the automotive industry in transition, 1996 (Box 21)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 21)
    - Valeo, 1999-2000 (Box 21)
    - Venturi, 2003 undated (Box 21)
    - Visteon, 1998 (Box 21)
    - Ward's Auto Report, 1996 (Box 21)
    - Zorea Consulting, LLC, 1990s-2000s (Box 21)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 21)
  - International
    The International subseries is arranged alphabetically by country or by company. This subseries documents Cole's international business relations, including his business activities with companies from Japan and France. Cole was on the Board of Directors for the French-American Business Association. The French Trade Commission materials contain an email sent to Cole that contains biographical information on his involvement in government organizations, the SAE, his education and employment history, research and a list of his publications.
    - Advics, 2002 (Box 22)
    - Africa, 1990s (Box 22)
    - Automotive Resources Asia (ARA), 1996-1997 (Box 22)
    - Australia
      - Automotive Industry Authority, 1990 (Box 22)
      - Barrack Group (Box 22)
      - Miscellaneous, 1980s-1990s (Box 22)
    - BMW, 1990s (Box 22)
    - Canada
      - Attain Technologies, 1990s (Box 22)
      - Science Council (Box 22)
      - Correspondence, 1990s-2000s (Box 22)
      - Automotive Competitiveness Review and presentations, 1980s-1990s (Box 22)
      - Reports and newsletters, 1980s-1990s (Box 22)
      - Annuals reports, 1991-1992 (Box 22)
    - China
      - Detroit Chinese Business Association, 1997 (Box 22)
      - "China Study -- Project II" (Box 22)
      - SPC Delegation and Cole's presentation, 1994 (Box 22)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 22)
    - Daimler Benz, 1990s (Box 22)
    - England
      - British Consulate (Box 22)
    - Fiat USA, Inc. (Associazione Tecnica dell'Autombile seminar and Italy), 1988; 1992 (Box 22)
    - France
      - French Trade Commission
        - Cole's biography and list of publications, 1992 (Box 22)
        - "What's the 'E' Future" seminar, 2001 (Box 22)
        - French-American Business Association, 2 folders (Box 22)
        - French-American Automotive Business Association, 1990s-2000s; 2 folders (Box 22)
      - Peugeot, 1989-1990 (Box 22)
      - Invest in France Agency, 1997-2002 (Box 22)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 22)
    - Germany
      - Fachhochschule Hamburg University of Applied Sciences, 1999 undated (Box 22)
    - Great Britain (Box 22)
    - Hungary, 1993 (Box 22)
    - Honda, 1980s-1990s (Box 22)
    - Hyundai, 1990s (Box 22)
    - India, 1990s (Box 22)
    - Indonesia (Texmaco Group), 1997 (Box 22)
    - Israel, 1995 (Box 22)
    - Italy, 1995 (Box 22)
    - Japan
      - Japan Automobile Manufacturers Association, Inc. (JAMA), 1998 (Box 23)
      - Institute for International Economic Studies (Box 23)
      - Mitsubishi Research Institute, 1980s-1990s (Box 23)
      - Presentation at TMM Suppliers meeting, 1995 (Box 23)
      - Clippings, 1990s (Box 23)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 23)
    - Kia Motors Corporation, 1991-1992 (Box 23)
    - Korea, 1990s undated (Box 23)
    - Mazda, 1980s-1990s; 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Mexico
      - Metalsa, 1992 (Box 23)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 23)
    - Netherlands, 1990s (Box 23)
    - Nissan, 1980s-1990s (Box 23)
    - Northern Ire, 1990-1991 (Box 23)
    - Norway, 1980s (Box 23)
    - Poland (Box 23)
    - Renault, 1990s (Box 23)
    - Russia, 1990s (Box 23)
    - Samsung, 2000s (Box 23)
    - SKF (Box 23)
    - Spain, 1989 undated (Box 23)
    - Sweden
      - Swedish-American Chamber of Commerce (SACC), 1990; 2000-2003 (Box 23)
      - Correspondence (includes photo), 1980s-1990s (Box 23)
      - International Journal of Vehicle Design, 1982 (Box 23)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 23)
    - Technova, 1980s (Box 23)
    - Thai, 1990s-2000s (Box 23)
    - Toyota
      - Annual reports and company information, 1990s-2000s (Box 23)
      - Correspondence, 1980s-2000s (Box 23)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 23)
    - VDI (Box 24)
    - Volkswagen
      - 1980s-1990s (Box 24)
      - 2003 (Box 24)
    - Volvo, 1995-1996 (Box 24)
    - World Business Council for Sustainable Development (WBCSD)
      - Sustainable Mobility Project, 2000s (Box 24)
      - Dialogue on Sustainable Mobility, 2001 (Box 24)
      - Paper on democratization of mobility, 1999 (Box 24)
      - Environmental reports and papers, 2000 undated (Box 24)
      - Publications, 1990s-2000s (Box 24)
- Correspondence